Everett Carll Ladd, Jr. Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Everett Carll Ladd, Jr. Papers
undated, 1959-2000.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.
51.2 linear feet.
The collection contains the professional papers of Dr. Ladd, professor of political science and director of the Roper Center at the University of Connecticut.
MSS20000038
Biography
Professor at University of Connecticut 1969-1999. Died 1999.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, reports, research notes and materials, publications, class materials, survey data and analysis all pertaining to Ladd's research on American politics. The collection has been inventoried and reboxed as necessary.
Arrangement
Series I: Inventory ( undated, 1960-2000 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to survey and public polling research as well as the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection. Call numbers have been included for those materials that have been cataloged and added to the collections:
Monographs:
Bruce-Biggs, B., ed. The New Class? Dodd B 5510
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Cantril, Albert H., ed. Polling on the Issues. Dodd B 5514
Donovan, John C., ed. Democracy at the Crossroads: An Introduction to American Government and Politics Dodd B 5508
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The American Ideology. An Exploration of the Origins, Meaning, and role of American Political Ideas. Dodd WE 117
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. American Political Parties: Social Change and Political Response. Dodd C 5504
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The American Polity: The People and Their Government Dodd C 5514
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The American Polity: The People and Their Government. Second ed. Dodd C 5500
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The American Polity: The People and Their Government. Third ed. Dodd C 5501
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. American Polity: The People and Their Government. Fourth ed. Dodd C 5502
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The American Polity: The People and Their Government. fifth ed. Dodd C 5503
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Ideology in America. Change and Response in a City, a Suburb, and a Small Town. Dodd A 4407
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr..The Ladd Report. Dodd C 5505
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Where Have All the Voters Gone? The Fracturing of America's Political Parties. Dodd B 5506
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Where Have All the Voters Gone? The Fracturing of America's Political Parties. Second ed. Dodd B 5507
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Attitudes Toward Economic Inequality. Dodd A4406
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Karlyn H. Bowman. Attitudes Toward the Environment. Twenty-Five Years after Earth Day. Dodd WGE 1
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Karlyn H. Bowman. Public Opinion about Abortion. Twenty-five Years after Roe v. Wade. Dodd WHQ 3
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Karlyn H. Bowman. Public Opinion in America and Japan. Dodd C 5507
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Karlyn H. Bowman. What's Wrong. A Survey of American Satisfaction and Complaint. Dodd C 5508
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. with Charles D. Hadley. Transformations of the American Party System. Political Coalitions from the New Deal to the 1970s. Dodd A 4408
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. The Divided Academy. Professors and Politics. Dodd B 5516, A 4409
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. Professors, Unions, and American Higher Education. Dodd C 5506
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. The United States in the 1980s. Dodd
Lipset, Seymour Martin, ed. Emerging Coalitions in American Politics. Dodd B 5515
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Lipset, Seymour Martin, ed. The Third Century, America as a Post-Industrial Society. Dodd B 5509
MacDonald, H. Malcolm, Wilfred D. Webb, Edward G. Lewis, William L. Strauss, eds. Readings in American Government. Fifth ed. Dodd A 4411
Mann, Thomas E. and Gary R. Orren, eds. Media Polls in American Politics. Dodd B 5504
Merton, Robert K., James S. Coleman, and Peter H. Rossi, eds. Qualitative and Quantitative Social Research. Papers in Honor of Paul E. Lazarsfeld. Dodd C 5498
Peterson, George E. and Carol W. Lewis, eds. Reagan and the Cities. Dodd B 5513
Pious, Richard M., ed. Presidents, Elections & Democracy. Essays from the Political Science Quarterly. Dodd C 5510
Rogers, Donald W., ed. Voting and the Spirit of American Democracy. Essays on the History of Voting and Voting Rights in America. Dodd B 5503
Salamon, Lester M. and Michael S. Lund, eds. The Reagan Presidency and the Governing of America. Dodd B 5512
Serow, Ann G., W. Wayne Shannon and Everett C. Ladd, eds. The American Polity Reader. Dodd C 5509
Periodicals:
America at the Polls 1994.
America at the Polls 1996.
America at the Polls 1998.
Change. v. 3, #3; v. 5, #6; 1971, 1973.
Connecticut. v. 35, #1, 1972.
Fortune. v. XCVI, #3-5; v. 98, #12; v. 99, #6; v. 100, #11; v. 101, #9; v. 102, #2, 8; v. 105, #12. 1977-1982.
Government Executive. v. 20, #1. January 1988.
The Ladd Report. #1-8 (2 copies of #3); and v. #1 (fourth edition).
Massachusetts Review. v. VIII, #2. Spring 1967.
Minerva: A Review of Science, Learning and Policy. v. VIII, #4; 1970.
The Nation. 1964-1965. v. 199, #5, 11; v. 200, #7.
Political Science Quarterly. v. 102, #3; v. 104, #1; v. 110, #1; 1987, 1989, 1995.
Polity: The Journal of the Northeastern Political Science Association. v. XXII, #3, Spring 1990.
PS: Political Science & Politics. v. XXIII, #2. June 1990.
Public Affairs Review. 1971, 1990.
Public Opinion. v. 1, #1, 3-4; v.3, #1, 3, 6; v. 4, #3; v. 5, #1, 4, 6; v. 6, #3-5v. 7, #2, 6; v. 8, #1, 3; v. 9, #2, 4; v. 10, #3; v. 11, #1, 5; v. 12, #1. 1978-1989.
The Public Opinion Quarterly. v. 35, #3; v. 40, #4; v. 43, #1; 1971, 1976-1977, 1979.
Public Perspective. 1989-1998 v. 1, #1-6; v. 2, #1-6; v. 3, #1-4, 5; v. 4, #3-6; v. 5, #1-6; v. 6, #1-3, 5-6; v. 7, #1-6; v. 9, #2.
Society. V. 24, #3. March/April 1987.
Sociology of Education. v. 47, #2. Spring 1974.
The South Atlantic Quarterly. v. LXV, #3, Summer 1966.
The Trojan Horse. v. 4, #9, 1964.
The Wilson Quarterly. v. 3, #2, 1979.
The Yale Review: A National Quarterly. v. LV, #1, Autumn 1965.
Reprints:
"Ladd Lipset Survey" Articles published in The Chronicle of Higher Education.
Outlook 1982.
Political Science Quarterly. v. 91, #4; v. 102, #3; v. 104, #1; v. 110, #1; v. 112, #1; 1976-1977,1987,1989, 1995, 1997.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. "Helvetius and D'Holbach "La moralisation de la politique." Reprinted from Journal of the History of Ideas. V. XXIII, #2, April-June 1962, pp. 221-238.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. "Hometown, U.S.A.: The Rise of Ideology." The South Atlantic Quarterly. v. LXVII, #1, Winter 1968.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. "Polling and the Press: The Clash of Institutional Imperatives." Public Opinion Quarterly. v. 44:5474-584. 1980.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. "The Polls: The Question of Confidence." The Public Opinion Quarterly. v. 40, #4, Winter 1976-1977.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. "The Radical Right: The White-Collar Extremists." The South Atlantic Quarterly. v. LXV, #3, Summer 1966.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Charles D. Hadley. "Party Definition and Party Differentiation." The Public Opinion Quarterly. v. 37, Spring 1973.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and and Seymour Martin Lipset. "American social scientists and the growth of campus political activism in the 1960s." Social Science Information. 10(2).
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "...And What Professors Think about Student protest and manners, morals, politcs and chaos on the campus." Psychology Today, November 1970.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "College generations-from the 1930s to the 1960s." The Public Interest, #25, Fall 1971.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "Contours of Academic Politics: 1972." American Enterprise Institute, #6.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "The Myth of the 'Conservative" Professor: A Reply to Michael Faia." Sociology of Education, v. 47, 1974.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "Politics of Academic Natural Scientists and Engineers." Science, v. 176, 1972. Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1972.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "Politics of American Sociologists." Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1972.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "Portrait of a Discipline: The American Political Science Community, Part I." Teaching Political Science, v. 2, #1, 1974.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset. "Portrait of a Discipline: The American Political Science Community, Part II." Teaching Political Science, v. 2, #2, 1975.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr., Charles Hadley and Lauriston King. "A New Political Realignment?" The Public Interest, #23, Spring 1971.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. with Marilyn Potter, Linda Basilik, Sally Daniels and Dana Suskiw. "The Polls: Taxing and Spending." Public Opinion Quarterly, 1979.
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Lipset, Seymour Martin. "Jewish Academics in the United States: Their Achievementsm, Culture and Politics." American Jewish Yearbook, 1971. 2 copies.
Papers:
Anderson B. R. O'G., Frederick A. Hargadon and Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.,eds. Selections from European Constitutions. Government 104, Cornell University, 1961. Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. The Congressional Parties: Cohesion and Conflict. Seminar in American Political Thought and Institutions/Professors Rossiter and Hacker. March 1960. Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. DeGaulle and Debre: A Comparative Study of Their Poltics and Roles in the Fifth French Republic. Comparative Government Seminar/Professor Mario Einaudi. April 1960. Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Parties and Politics in Canada. Seminar in Comparative Government/Professor Steven Muller. December 1960 Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr.. Political Parties, 'Reform,' and American Democracy. Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and G. Donald Ferree, Jr., The Voting System, The Policy System, and the Current Malaise of Representative Government in the U.S. Prepared for presentation at the 1979 Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Washington, D.C., 1979. Dodd
Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. and Charles D. Hadley. Political Parties and Political Issues: Patterns in Differentiation Since the New Deal. American Politics Series. V. 1. Beverly Hills: Sage Publications, 1973. Ohio State University. Dodd
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Faculty--Correspondence.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.); United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Subjects:
Elections United States 20th century.; Public opinion polls--United States.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Diaries.; Audio cassettes.; Audio visual materials.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Diskettes, Floppy.; Books.
Occupations:
xxx
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Cynthia Ladd in 2000.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1960-2000
  - Correspondence, A - Boston Globe, undated, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Bradey Foundation - Conference Board, undated, 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Consulting Activities - Dodd Research Center, undated, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Dunphy Scholarship - Heline, Holly, undated, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Kennedy School Book - Latham, Scott, undated (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Latin American - Newsday, undated, 1991-1997 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Nichols College - Renner, Douglas, undated, 1992-1999 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, Renshon, Stanley - Steinmo, Sven, undated, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Strata Comm - University Printing, undated (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, University Relations - Zalatimo, Dawud, undated (Box 10)
  - Ladd Correspondence, American's Talk Security - Kohut, Andrew, undated, 1962-1995 (Box 11)
  - Ladd Correspondence, L - Personal (Ladd), undated, 1989-1997 (Box 12)
  - Ladd Correspondence, Reader's Digest Billing - Rubin, Richard, undated, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Ladd Correspondence, Saint Michaels College - Yankelovich, Skelly, and White, undated, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Public Perspectives, A - D, undated, 1983-1992 (Box 15)
  - Public Perspectives, D - Z, undated (Box 16)
  - Public Perspectives, undated, 1985-1994 (Box 17)
  - Everett C. Ladd Seminars, undated, 1969-1992 (Box 18)
  - Everett C. Ladd Seminars, undated, 1985-1995 (Box 19-21)
  - Everett C. Ladd Publications, undated, 1974-1979 (Box 21)
  - Everett C. Ladd Seminars, undated (Box 22)
  - Everett C. Ladd Publications, undated, 1962-1995 (Box 22-33)
  - Publications, Day files, correspondence, undated, 1988-1999 (Box 33)
  - Day files, notes, syllabus, undated, 1976-1999 (Box 34)
  - Publications, research, email, correspondence, memorial, survey data, undated, 1968-2000 (Box 35)
  - Research data, photograph, publications, undated, 1960-1995 (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, financial records, Roper Center history, research, notes, undated, 1968-1999 (Box 37)
  - VHS tapes, undated, 1995-1997 (Box 38)
  - Audio cassettes, undated, 1976-1998 (Box 39)
  - Paper, Lectures, 1959, 1978 (Box 40)